let's look at the solution to this part
of our BTB and BHT quiz the question now
is which of the four BTB entries do we
use for each of these instructions leave
the field blank if none is used we
already know that we use the BTB ones
here and a hundred times here and that's
all of the BTB uses so the only
instructions that we really need to put
something for is this and this how do we
determine which BTB the entry do we use
well we'll look at the address in just
the same way that we did it for the BHT
in this case the address is C zero zero
eight the BTB has four entries we take
the lowermost
two bits in this case because we need
two bits to tell us which of the four
entries but we don't use the bits that
are always the same for all instructions
in this case the lowermost two bits so
really this is the number of the BTB
entry for the c00 eight instruction one
zero is 2 so we will use the entry
number two the other instruction that we
need to figure out is at redress C 0 1 C
so it's gonna be C 0 1 C again ignore
the lowermost bits that stay the same
take the next two bits because we need
to know which of the 4 entries to use
and we get 1 1 which corresponds to the
entry number 3 as you can see only
entries number 2 & 3 are used in this
loop if this instruction were a taken
branch it would have used an entry
number 0 this one would have used 1 2 3
and then because we have 4 entries this
one again would be using entry number 0
1 2 3 but because these are the only
ones that actually use these entries all
we have to do is access the entry number
2 here it's accessed once if you
remember and access the entry number 3
here it's accessed a hundred times if
you remember